klipland.com 2019-03-24

# Privacy and cookies | Klipland.com

On the Klipland.com website, as data managers we inform you about how we process your personal information on our site and what we use them for. We will use your personal information exclusively for information purposes in case you are subscribed to newsletter and for the benefit of a better user experience. The collected personal data will be protected in accordance with ZVOP-1, ZVOP-2, ZPT-1B and GDPR.

If you are interested in additional explanations, you can always contact us at [info@klipland.com](mailto:info@klipland.com)

### Usage, scope and purpose of storing and processing your data

When you register on our website Klipland.com, some of your personal information are saved in our database. We keep your chosen username, or name and surname if you register via the Facebook plug-in and the email address. We do not save your other personal information in our database at the time of registration. If you upload a picture on your profile, it is transferred to our server, and the link to the image is saved in the database.  
When you add a comment to a specific article, we save the contents of your comment and your username in our database.  
If you subscribe to newsletter only, your e-mail address is saved in our database.

Each time you visit our site, the following information is automatically collected, which can be collected and processed on third-party cookies by third parties, more specifically the Google Analytics tool:

  * Specifications that include the Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and version, operating system and platform, type of device

  * Information about your visit, including the URL link and the content you've viewed, the duration of visits to specific pages, and the number of impressions visited

We process your personal information for the better user experience and easier use of our website Klipland.com. We won't share your personal data with third parties.

### Storing

We store collections of your personal information in the territory of the Slovenia, and we don't share them to other countries or other individuals.

### Storing time

We store personal data until the consent for the storage and processing of individual data is revoked.

### Individual rights

Every individual can make a request for us at any time for this information:

  * Insights

  * Correction

  * Interruption of consent for processing and storing

  * Cancellation

If an individual believes that his or her rights have been violated from our website at any time, he or she can make make a complaint at our e-mail address info@klipland.com or to the Information Commissioner in the Republic of Slovenia or your country. We will do everything to help individuals to exercise their rights!

* * *

## About cookies

Cookies are usually small text files, given ID tags that are stored on your computer's browser directory or program data subfolders. Cookies are created when you use your browser to visit a website that uses cookies to keep track of your movements within the site, help you resume where you left off, remember your registered login, theme selection, preferences, and other customization functions.The website stores a corresponding file(with same ID tag)to the one they set in your browser and in this file they can track and keep information on your movements within the site and any information you may have voluntarily given while visiting the website, such as email address.  
Cookies are often indispensable for websites that have huge databases, need logins, have customizable themes, other advanced features.  
Cookies usually don't contain much information except for the url of the website that created the cookie, the duration of the cookie's abilities and effects, and a random number. Due to the little amount of information a cookie contains, it usually cannot be used to reveal your identity or personally identifying information.However, marketing is becoming increasingly sophisticated and cookies in some cases can be agressively used to create a profile of your surfing habits.  
There are two types of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies are created temporarily in your browser's subfolder while you are visiting a website. Once you leave the site, the session cookie is deleted. On the other hand, persistent cookie files remain in your browser's subfolder and are activated again once you visit the website that created that particular cookie. A persistent cookie remains in the browser's subfolder for the duration period set within the cookie's file.

#### How our website uses cookies

Cookie is a short text that our website sends to browser. This is how website knows what you're interested in, what language do you prefer and other settings. This is how your next visit is easier. Cookies has very important role.  
We do not send datas from cookies to anyone, we just use them for better user experience and statistic.

#### Which cookies do we use and what is their purpose

Here you can see names of cookies our website uses, what is their purpose and how long do they stay saved in your browser.

 **Cookie name**|  **Duration**|  **Purpose**  
---|---|---  
PHPSESSID| session| Session cookie that our portal uses it for PHP configuration  
__utma| 1 minute| Cookie for statistic in Google Analytics  
__utmb| 30 minutes| Cookie for statistic in Google Analytics  
__utmc| session| Cookie for statistic in Google Analytics  
__utmz| 6 months| Cookie for statistic in Google Analytics  
gnk_g| 1 month| Rotation for graphic adverts  
isp| 1 month| Caching for the purpose of distributing ads  
seen| 6 months| Cookie for better user experience  
liked| session| Session cookie for better user experience  
facebookbox| 1 month| Cookie for better user experience  
hidden| 1 year| Cookie for better user experience
